（フリーセル）カイト…　パズルをしよう…。
（カイト）あっ。
Kaito, let's puzzle.
どうしたの？
僕を救うんじゃなかったの？
What's wrong? Weren't you going to save me?
見えるよ…　カイト…
僕たちのパズルタイムが…。
I can see it, Kaito.
I can see our puzzle time.
心の声
（フリーセル）なぜだ…　なぜ　井藤ノノハが
僕とカイトの未来に現れる？
Why? Why is Itou Nonoha in the future of Kaito and me?
lost te saguri de sagashiteta
Lost, trying to find it blindly with my hands.
tozasareta mirai no kotae nante doko ni mo nai
But the key to the locked future is nowhere to be found.
hashiru shoudou ima kaidoku funou
Undecipherable urges surging.
found kudaketa hazu no unmei wo
I found the fate I believed broken.
mijukuna yume no naka de kikoetekitan da
I heard it in my immature dream.
saigo made I'll be there for you
I'll be there for you till the very end.
tachitomaranai kono hari dake wa
I can't stop. I hear nothing else.
boku no asu wo kizamu oto tsukisasu
How this needle carves my future.
shinjitsu kara nigetara ima
I'm running away from the truth now.
genjitsu ni mo maketara ima
I'm losing to reality now.
nani ga nokoru no (nokoru no)
What will be left?
kazoekirenai kono kizu dake ga
The countless scars on my body
boku no kinou wo zanzou toshite kataru
are the only thing telling the story of my past.
unmei ga hodokete mo ima
Even if fate falls apart now,
sonzai wo kowashite mo ima
even if existence shatters now,
boku no michi wo yuku yo
I'm walking down my own path.
It's now or never.
This is what they say: "Live your life today."
There will always be, there will always be a way.
A Closed World
（ソウジ）本当に　そう言ったんだね。
Are you sure he said that?
Yes. Pinochle said Freecell's waiting for me at the Puzzle of God.
ああ。　神のパズルで待ってるって。
ピノクルに　伝言を。
（ギャモン）ぶったまげたな。　まさか
ここで　神のパズルが出てくるとはよ。
This caught me off guard.
I didn't expect the Puzzle of God to come up now.
ピタゴラス伯爵と　ジンが戦ったのが
神のパズルだったよな。
Count Pythagoras and Jin fought at the Puzzle of God, right?
（ルーク）ああ。　だけど　あれは
戦いのあと　崩壊してしまった。
Yeah, but it was destroyed after the fight.
（ビショップ）他にあるかどうか　今の
ＰＯＧでは確認できていません。
Not even the POG knows if there are others.
（キュービック）
どうしろって言うんだ…。
What should we do then?
The Puzzle of God is a puzzle that only two Phi Brains fighting to the death can solve.
神のパズルとは　２人のファイ・ブレインが
命を懸けなければ→
決して解けないパズル。
うおっ。
But I'm not a Phi Brain.
けど　俺は　ファイ・ブレインじゃねえ。
（ルーク）今はね。
あっ。
Not yet.
フリーセルは　なぜ　クロンダイクから
ファイナル・リングを奪ったのか…。
Why did Freecell take the Final Ring from Klondike?
彼は　すでに　本物に匹敵するリングを
手に入れているのにね。
He had a ring of equal power already.
考えられる理由は…。
（アナ）ああ！
The only reason I can think of is...
（ノノハ）カイト…。
Kaito!
Rook, could you locate Freecell through the POG?
ルーク　ＰＯＧの力で　フリーセルの居所を
見つけてくれねえか。
行くんだね。
ああ。
You're going?
Yeah.
相手が　バケモンでもか？
Even if your opponent is a monster?
お前に勝ったクロンダイクを　あっさり
乗り越えた野郎だぞ！
You lost to Klondike, but he defeated him in a flash!
俺は約束を…　フリーセルと　パズルタイムを
始めるって約束を果たす。
I must fulfill my promise
to have puzzle time with him.
そんで　あいつを助け出す！
Then I'll save him!
（エレナ）こんな形で　クロンダイクの野望が
ついえるなんて→
I didn't expect Klondike's plan to fall apart like this.
予想もしなかったわね。
（ダウト）協力　感謝する。
I appreciate your help.
帰りましょう。　少し休むといいわ。
Let's go home. We should rest a bit.
ありがとう。
Thanks.
どうした？　ピノクル。
What's wrong, Pinochle?
フリーセルか。
Freecell?
僕には　フリーセルの暴走が
悲鳴に聞こえたんだ…。
When he went berserk, that sounded like a scream to me.
悲しかった…。
It was sad...
あぁ…。
（フリーセル）カイト。
あっ！
Kaito...
フリーセル…。
カイト…　パズルをしよう…。
Freecell?!
Kaito, let's do a puzzle!
どうしたの？
僕を救うんじゃなかったの？
What's wrong? Weren't you going to save me?
見えるよ　カイト…
僕たちのパズルタイムが。
I can see it, Kaito.
I can see our puzzle time.
あはっ。
夢…　また未来を…　今は　何時だ！？
A dream...
I saw the future again.
What time is it now?
What?!
何だと！？
フリーセル　何を考えてる！
Freecell, what are you thinking?!
（ホイストの声）「井藤ノノハ様は
私どもの所におられます。→
Ms. Itou Nonoha is with us now.
フリーセル様ともども　神のパズルにて→
Along with Lord Freecell, we are waiting for Sir Daimon Kaito's arrival.
大門カイト様のお越しを
お待ちしております。→
場所は…」。
The location is...
[TEL]（ルーク）　指定された座標上には
確かに　謎の巨大施設がある。
There actually is a mysterious giant structure at the designated coordinates.
[TEL]　所有者は　おそらく
レーベンヘルツ財団…。
Its owner is probably the Löwenherz Foundation.
あっ！　ノノハに　つけてあった
発信器が　座標上に…。
Nonoha's tracker is at those coordinates too!
どうやら　間違いねえようだな。
Looks like there's no mistake.
[TEL]（ルーク）　カイト　敵の狙いが
まだ　よく分からない。
Kaito, we still don't know what the enemy wants.
[TEL]　こっちも　もう少し
調べてみるけど　油断はしないで。
We'll keep investigating, just don't let your guard down.
ああ　分かった。　ありがとな。
I know. Thanks.
人質とは　バッチイまね　しやがる。
ノノハに何かあったら　許さねえ！
Taking hostages isn't exactly fair play.
He'll pay if something happens to Nonoha.
人質なんか取らなくたって
カイトは約束を守るのに…。
Kaito would go to fulfill his promise even if they didn't take a hostage.
彼は分かってないね。
Doesn't he know that?
それも　気になるところなんだ。
That's something that worries me too.
ノノハ君は
ただの人質なんだろうか…。
Is Nonoha really just a hostage?
えっ！？
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
それは分からないんだけど。
I don't have anything concrete...
Either way, we'll have to meet Freecell to find out.
とにかく　フリーセルに会ってみなきゃ
分かんねえってこった。
（ホイスト）どうぞ。
Please have some.
どうぞじゃないわよ！
どうぞじゃ！
Have some?! Cut the crap!
と言いますと…。
What do you mean?
I came because he said he wanted to talk.
彼が　私と話したがってるって
いうから　来てあげたのに…。
So what the heck is this place? Where am I?
何なのよ　ここ？　どこなのよ！？
（ホイスト）ヒマラヤ山中でございます。
ヒ　ヒラマヤ！？
We are in the Himalayas.
Hi-Hilamaya?
ヒマラヤでございます。
Himalayas.
あ～！　信じらんない…。
話しするのに　ヒラマヤって…。
I can't believe this. Why do we have to talk in the Hilama—
Well, it was weird that a plane came to pick me up...
余計なことをしてくれたね　ホイスト。
I didn't ask for this, Whist.
申し訳ございません。
I am sorry.
But to actually begin the game...
しかし　確実にゲームを始めるためで
ございますゆえ…。
まあ　いい。　彼女という
存在については　少し興味がある。
Whatever.
I'm a bit curious about her anyway.
で　今度は　何の悪だくみ？
ハハハッ　そう　カリカリしないで。
So what are you scheming this time?
You don't have to be so offensive.
Whist's tea is really good.
ホイストのいれるお茶は　絶品なんだ。
冷めないうちに　どうぞ。
Have some before it gets cold.
We haven't met since we saved Kaito together.
（フリーセル）あの時以来だね。
一緒にカイトを助けた…。
ああ　うまっ…　あっ　フフン　そうね。
Oh my god, that's good!
Yes, indeed.
未来を見たんだ。
そこにカイトだけじゃなく　君も居た。
I've seen the future.
Not only Kaito, but you were there too.
なぜなのかな？
あっ。
Why?
How am I supposed to know that?
そんなの　私に
分かるわけないじゃない。
君が　カイトを全然理解してないって
ことは　分かるけどね。
I know that you don't understand Kaito at all.
僕が　カイトを…。
I don't?
そう　人質なんか取らなくても
カイトは約束を守るのに。
You don't have to take hostages to make him fulfill his promise.
カイトが　約束を？
もう　そんなの　どうでもいいよ。
Kaito and his promise?
Who cares about that now?
ここに来るのは
決められた未来だから。
It's our destiny to come here.
あっ。　どうでもよくない！
We care about it!
カイトが言ったんだから。
「約束を果たす」って。
Kaito said he's gonna fulfill his promise.
あっ…　ホント？　ホントに？
Really?
Did he really?
カイトが　そう言ったの？
えっ！？
Kaito said that?
Huh?
そうか…　カイトが　僕との約束を…。
I see...
Kaito wants to fulfill his promise.
フッ　フフフフッ。　ハハハッ　ハハハハッ。
何　それ？
What now?
カイトとの約束なんか
どうでもいいんじゃなかったの？
I thought you didn't care about that promise anymore.
ハハハッ！
あっ　そうだ。
Oh, right.
I've been meaning to do this.
ちょうど　いいわ。
フフフフフフッ。
これ　返す。
I'm giving this back.
お母さんの形見。
やっぱり　君が持ってるべきよ。
You should have your mother's memento.
ああ…　まただ。
Again...
君は　僕に思い出したくもない事を
思い出させる。
You make me remember stuff I don't want to remember.
あの日も…。
あっ。
That day too...
ノノハ…　無事で　いろよ…。
心の声
Nonoha, be careful...
（フリーセル）これはね　パズルなんだよ。
でも　どうしても解けなくて…。
You know, this is a puzzle.
But I couldn't solve it no matter what.
あっ。
アハハッ。
変だな…
これだけは　今でも解けないや。
It's weird. I still can't solve it.
カイトに　一緒に
解いてもらいたかったのは→
I wanted to ask Kaito to solve it with me.
このパズルだったんだ。
このパズルを解いて
ママを喜ばせたかったから。
I wanted to solve this puzzle to make Mama happy.
あっ。
でも　今の僕には　どうでもいい。
But that doesn't matter to me anymore.
約束も…　ママも…。
Nor does the promise and Mama...
ソリティア…。
ん？
Solitaire...
君のママよね。
あっ　どうして　ママの名前を？
She was your mother, right?
How do you know Mama's name?
ソリティアさんは…　君のママは…→
Solitaire, your mother...
レプリカ・リングの最初の犠牲者。
はっ。
was the first victim of the replica rings.
回想　（ソリティアの日記）
「私は今　苦しみの中にある。→
I am suffering.
回想
光に満たされるような幸福と
地の底から噴き出すような悪意。→
Happiness as bright as sunlight
and hatred as dark as a graveyard.
交互に襲いかかる
回想
感情の波に　私は翻弄されている。→
The waves of this storm are laying siege to my heart.
フリーセルを愛しているのに→
回想
I love Freecell, but the next moment, I may find myself hating him.
次の瞬間には
回想
憎んでいる自分がいる。→
Why?
回想
なぜ　この子に　ほほ笑みかけて
あげることができないのだろう」。
Can I not smile at my own child?
君の昔の家で見つけた日記に
書かれていた…　これが真実…。
That was written in a diary found in your old house.
That is the truth.
リングのせいで　心をゆがめられ→
Her heart was warped by the ring,
いいママと　悪いママとの間で
もがき苦しんで…。
and she was suffering from the duality of being a good and a bad mother.
分かったでしょう。
君のママは　君を愛していたのよ。
Do you get it?
Your mother loved you!
Oh, really...?
ちょっ…　それだけ！？
衝撃の真実なのよ。
Is that it? Shouldn't the truth be more shocking?
もっと喜んでも　いいんじゃない！？
Would it bother you to show some happiness?
Knowing her past won't change how much I hate her.
そんなこと言われても　大嫌いな
ママの過去を知ったところで→
別に…。
ん。
I'm telling you your mother was actually kind, and it was all the ring's fault!
だから　君のママは
本当は優しくて　悪いのは　リングで！
すごいよね　君。
はぁ？
You're really amazing.
Huh?
１回読んだだけで　日記を全部
暗記できるんでしょう？
You memorized that diary after reading it just once, right?
So, what else was written in there?
ねえ　ママの日記には
他に　なんて書いてあったの？
分かりました。
I understand.
構いません。　ゲートを開けて下さい。
It's okay. Open the gates, please.
あのう…。
はい。
Um...
Yes?
Can I have a pen and some paper?
すみません。
紙とペンを貸してもらえますか。
はい　これ。
ん？
Here, this is it.
うわ～っ！　これ　小さい頃に
ママが作ってくれたパズルだ！
Ah, that's a puzzle Mama made me when I was little!
アハハハハッ　懐かしいなぁ！
あっ。
This brings back some memories.
アハハハハッ。　ああ　ここが　これだ。
Ah, this goes here.
何なの？　その笑顔…。
心の声
Why is he smiling so brightly?
大嫌いな　お母さんが
作ったパズルなのに…。
It's a puzzle from the mother he hates.
（キュービック）大規模な施設だね。
This facility is huge.
It must've been the Foundation's secret research laboratory.
財団の秘密研究所って
とこだろうけど…。
You can see Nonoha's signal, right?
ノノハの反応は　出てるんだな？
うん。　発信器には近づいてるよ。
Yeah, we're getting closer to the tracker.
I've got a bad feeling about this. It's too easy.
（ギャモン）
気味が悪いくれえ　順調だな。
心の声
お母さんが　大好きで　大嫌い。
He loves and hates his mother.
He doesn't care about Kaito's promise,
心の声
カイトとの約束は　どうでもよくて
でも　守ってくれると　うれしい。
but he's happy if he fulfills it.
矛盾した２つの思い。
心の声
Two feelings that contradict each other.
He's in a closed world, bound by those feelings.
それに縛られて…
心の声
閉じた世界を作って…→
そこから出られなくなっている…。
He can't escape.
オルペウス・リングのせいで！
心の声
It's because of the Orpheus ring.
フリーセル君！　リングを外そう！
Freecell, take off the ring!
これ以上　リングをつけてちゃ
いけないよ！
You shouldn't wear the ring anymore!
解けた！
分からないの？　君の
ママも　２つの思いの間で苦しんで。
I solved it!
Don't you get it? Your mother suffered from the same duality!
あっ。
えっ！？　何？
Huh, what?
気付かなかったよ…　このパズルに
もう一つ　答えがあることに…。
I never realized... This puzzle had one more solution.
同じ数字の文字を集めて
並べ替えると…。
If you take the letters of the same number and reorder them...
「あなたは　私の希望」。
"You are my hope."
あぁ？　えっ！？　ちょっと？　何？
Hey! What are you...?!
髪を　下ろしてくれない？
はっ？
Would you let your hair down?
何よ　いきなり…。
お願い！
Why are you asking that?
Please!
ママに　そっくりだ。
You look just like Mama.
ママのペンダントをして
ママの日記を暗記してて…→
You're wearing her pendant... You memorized her diary...
僕の知らないママの思いも
知っている。
You know more about Mama's feelings than I do.
君は…　僕のママだ。
You're my Mama!
Watch me, Mama!
見ていて　ママ。　もうすぐ
カイトとのパズルタイムが始まる。
I'll have my puzzle time with Kaito soon.
カイトは　僕の永遠の憧れ。
I'll adore Kaito forever.
僕も　カイトになるんだ。
I'll become Kaito!
（エレナ）何ですって？
カイトが　フリーセルのところへ！？
What? Kaito went to Freecell?
あっ　分かったわ。
（ダウト）本当なのか？
I get it.
Is it true?
そうみたいね。
お願いだ。　僕たちも　そこへ。
It seems so.
Please! Let's go there!
そのつもりよ。
That's what I've been planning.
（アナ）広いとこに出た。
This place is big.
フリーセルとノノハは　ここに居るのか？
（キュービック）そのはずだけど…。
Are Freecell and Nonoha here?
It seems like it, but...
あっ！
お待ちしておりました。
ホイスト！
We've been waiting for you.
Whist!
てめえ！　ノノハは　どこだ？
とっとと　返しやがれ！
Hey, fuck-ass! Where's Nonoha?!
Give her back right now!
Sir Daimon Kaito. I've observed your numerous activities until now.
大門カイト様　今日までの
幾多のご活躍を拝見して→
私は確信しました。
Thus I am now sure
あなたは　フリーセル様と
互角に戦える存在だと。
that you can fight on par with Lord Freecell.
ホイスト　何者なんだ　お前…。
Whist, just who the hell are you?
Someone who desires the manifestation of the Orpheus Order's goal on this Earth.
オルペウス・オーダーの大義が
地上に顕現することを望む者。
ソリティアのように…。
うっ。
Just like Solitaire.
フリーセルの母親の名前を…　なんで？
How do you know the name of Freecell's mother?
私も彼女も　人類を幸福へと導く
超人の誕生を望んでいました。
Both of us have wished for the birth of a superhuman who would lead mankind to prosperity.
クロンダイクは　そのための
道具にすぎません。
Klondike was merely a tool to achieve that.
神を創ろうというのか？
いいえ　人が神を超えるのです！
Do you want to create a god?
No. Mankind will surpass their gods.
この戦いに勝利した者こそが→
Whoever wins this battle
人類を解放するオルペウス・リングの
真の所有者なのです！
will be the bearer of the true Orpheus ring that will lead mankind to freedom!
さあ　始めましょう。
超人誕生の儀式を。
Let us begin the ceremony of a superhuman's birth.
（一同）あっ！
ノノハ！
Nonoha!
Kaito!
カイト！…　みんな！
Guys!
何とも　ねえのか？
ケガは？
Are you okay?
Are you hurt?
うん　大丈夫。
来てくれてありがとう。
I'm fine.
Thanks for coming.
D-Did he do something to you?
（ギャモン）いや　やややや　やつに
何か　されたんじゃねえのか！？
え～と　特には。
一緒に　お茶飲んで　パズルして…。
Nothing really.
We had a tea together, solved a puzzle...
パズル？
はい　ソリティアさんの作ったパズルを。
A puzzle?
Yeah, a puzzle made by Solitaire.
そしたら　私のこと
ママとか言い出して。
Then he started calling me "Mama".
それじゃあ　そろそろ
消えてもらおうかな　ホイスト。
I think it's time for you to get lost,
Whist.
うっ…。
僕の見た未来に　君の姿はない。
You're not in the future I've seen.
たぶん　カイトの見る未来にもね。
Probably not in the future Kaito's seen either.
あっ！
（ホイスト）フリーセル様　私は→
Lord Freecell... I wish to serve whoever wins this battle.
あなたか　大門カイト様
どちらか勝った方に　お仕えを…。
No one asked for that.
目障りなんだよね。
カイトと僕の神聖にして　最後のゲーム
君の目で　汚されたくない。
This is the last, holy game between me and Kaito.
I don't want your presence to defile it.
ですが…。
But...
消えろ！
ぬっ！
Get lost!
カイト　君は僕を救いたいんだよね。
Kaito, you want to save me, right?
救ってよ。
ゲームに勝って　リングを外してよ。
Then save me by winning this game!
Take this ring off of me!
（床が割れる音）
（ギャモン）あっ！？　何だ　おい！
What's going on?
（フリーセル）でも　残念だけどね
今の君じゃあ　勝てないよ。
But sadly, you can't win as you are now.
Want to come over and try?
僕のところまで来て
試してみるかい？
えっ…　うっ！
カイト！
Kaito!
フフフッ…　僕と一緒じゃなきゃ
始まらない…。
It won't begin unless we're together.
これは…。
ファイナル・リングさ。
What's this?!
The final ring.
これで　君も　ファイ・ブレインになる。
Now you'll become a Phi Brain too!
（一同）あっ！？
ファイナル・リングだって！？
The final ring?!
やっぱり　クロンダイクから奪ったのは
このためだったのか。
So he did take it from Klondike for this!
Both Kaito and I can become gods now.
（フリーセル）僕とカイトが
神となる資格を得たとき→
僕の作った神のパズルは
完成するんだ。
The Puzzle of God I made will be complete!
Stop, Kaito!
ダメだよ　カイト！
リングに飲み込まれちゃったら→
If the ring overwhelms you, who will save Freecell?!
誰が　フリーセル君を救うのよ！
ダメ～！
No!
（フリーセル）あはっ！
（一同）あはっ…。
カイト…。
あっ。
Kaito...
こんな力を借りなくても
俺は　お前と戦えるぜ…　フリーセル！
I don't need this power to fight you!
Freecell!
あっ！？　フフフフッ　すごい…
やっぱり　君は　すごいよ。　カイト！
Amazing!
You're truly amazing, Kaito!
見えるかい？
あれが　僕の作った神のパズルさ。
Can you see it? This is the Puzzle of God I made.
行こうか。
いいとも。
Shall we go?
We shall.
うわわっ！
へっ。
はっ。
へい。
行っちゃった…。
カイト…。
They left...
Kaito...
（ギャモン）あの野郎…　力ずくで
リングを拒否しやがった。
He rejected the ring by force.
（キュービック）
もう　カイトは　オルペウス・リングすら→
Kaito doesn't need an Orpheus ring anymore.
必要としない存在に
なっているんだよ。
フリーセルは　自分の望む閉じた世界を
作ろうとしていた…。
Freecell tried to complete the closed world he wished for.
If their power proves to be equal,
もし　２人の力が互角だったら…→
永遠に戻ってこられない。
they'll never return!
eiyuu kidori itsu datte shinjita muteki no kankaku
I think I'm a hero and believe that I'm invincible.
tatakatte iru no wa chikyuu no tame nanka janai
I'm not fighting for the world.
motto mai peesu de
It's for a more personal,
sou motto shoujikina negai no tame
a more honest wish.
nando to naku kizutsuite mo
No matter how many times I'm hurt